Around our world.
Stop me up!
Oh
What's the matter, Robin?
You have to tell me,
didn't my mom come by here?
Now hold on a minute.
Where did that come from?
Why would you think your
mother was back in Ohara?
I've severed all bonds.
No matter what, I can't let her
become the daughter of a criminal.
I wish she was here, too, but she's not.
Oh, yeah!
We're in trouble!
I heard there are navy battleships
coming to the island right now!
They're trying to get rid of
all the scholars on Ohara!
The people in town must
be stirring up bad rumors.
The truth is, that's no battleship, and
they won't be getting rid of anyone.
The government is paying
us a visit, though.
And that means the library
will be under an investigation.
A harsh one.
So listen up.
No matter what those
government agents say or do,
you absolutely cannot let them know?
that you're an archaeologist
like the rest of us.
Since you're so young,
as long as you keep quiet, no
one will think you're a scholar.
You understand?
Move it!
Stop what you're doing!
Put your hands in the air and go outside!
Don't you think you're
being a bit violent?
The researchers here at
the Tree of Knowledge
are being charged with the heinous crime?
of deciphering poneglyphs.
We'll be investigating the library,
so everyone get out of our
way and leave the building.
You'd better treat this place with care.
The value of this collection is well
beyond your imagination, I assure you.
I don't have to listen to a word you say.
Take him outside! Yes, sir!
Attention, citizens of Ohara!
I regret to inform you that
the scholars of this island
may be devils in disguise plotting
to destroy the world. What? But why?
Our scholars are the pride
of every person in Ohara.
They would never dream of
doing something like that.
From this point forward,
we will be conducting a large-scale
search of the entire island.
During that time,
all those who are not related to
the research center must take a form
of identification and head to the
evacuation ship on the West Seashore.
Evacuation?
That's ridiculous!
Even if the scholars did do something
wrong that still has nothing to do with us,
you can't kick us off our own island!
Our only obligation was to
pass on this message to you.
Disregard our warning if you like,
but we won't be held responsible,
should any unfortunate accidents occur.
You heard him?
Yeah, everyone!
Back in the West Shore!
I don't want to have
any part of this mess!
I've been shot!
This is it for me!
I'm a gunner, dammit! A gunner!
Contact the higher-ups!
Tell them I want my son to take
over for me! Calm down, Chief.
Just take a look.
The bullet went through
your sleeve, that's all.
Oh, I see.
I'll aim to kill next time.
Well, if it isn't Nico Olvia.
I find it hard to believe that a
devious criminal like you would end
up on this island completely by
coincidence after your daring escape.
In other words,
despite the fact that you've denied your
connection to the Scholars of O 'Hara,
You've shown up at their doorstep just in
time to warn them of our
little investigation.
Now, in my humble opinion, that very clearly
labels them as your partners in crime.
You've no idea why I'm here.
That doesn't prove one single thing.
I'm sure you've cooked up plenty
of excuses to cover for them.
You're a clever woman, after all.
But that doesn't really matter,
because we don't have to prove your
connection to the Ohara scholars anymore.
Now that we're here, we can search
every little nook and cranny.
I doubt it'll take long before we find
evidence of their poneglyph research.
The government's quite confident in
this, and you know they're never wrong.
This has been in the
works for a long time.
Capturing you after six years of hide-and-seek
was nothing more than the final push.
There are plenty of poneglyph
researchers around the world,
and each time we captured one,
we tried to find any connection
they might have to Ohara.
Can you guess why that is?
Don't tell me.
You're making an example of us?
Exactly.
If we crush this holy
ground of archaeology,
the entire academic
world will take notice.
It's the perfect opportunity
to show the world exactly
what happens to those who
research the blank century.
Then, the battleships from headquarters
waiting on standby are here, too.
Well, look at that.
You are a clever woman, aren't you?
Yes, as you might guess, there to ensure
that not even a single criminal escapes.
However, as a matter of form, we
still need to verify their guilt.
We aren't pirates, after all.
So I came all this way to conduct
a compulsory investigation
of the island and chase off
anyone who's not involved.
It's curtains for you and your friends.
There's no escape.
Take her down.
Hey, what are you doing?
All the books here are world treasures.
Take them outside and shut them up.
Move it, you bastards.
They must have a secret
room somewhere around here.
Don't stop until you find it.
This is worse than I thought.
The battleships are here already
and there's a whole mess of them.
That should be everyone.
Good, now don't let them go anywhere.
Look, they're rounding
up all the scholars.
What did they do wrong?
They say they were cooking up
a plan to destroy the world.
That can't be true.
Where is the evacuation ship?
It's on the west seashore.
Hurry!
Everyone, run!
Who knows what might happen?
Robin, they said there's
an evacuation ship waiting.
We don't know what the government
is going to do anymore.
You should get out while you can. No way!
There's nothing but mean
people on that stupid boat.
I'm staying here with my friends.
Robin!
I'm the same as you, aren't I?
That's enough!
Just go!
Looks like you have the
situation under control.
Thank you very much, Chief!
I was quite surprised.
Nobody warned me there were such
ferocious beasts wandering the island.
But it makes for a fine trophy, huh?
Olivia?
All right, listen carefully.
This woman is an escaped prisoner.
We executed her comrades
after we found out
that they'd been
deciphering ancient texts.
But we still have a couple
of matters left to clear up.
So let me be frank here.
If she's your partner,
just come out with it already so I
can get this over with and go home.
How awful of them to
hurt someone like that.
Robin, for the last time, go! Hurry!
Robin?
Robin, my little girl,
you've grown so much.
Olvia.
What are they doing?
If they're not careful, they're
going to burn the whole tree down.
I never thought they would
take such drastic measures.
Wow, they aren't holding back, are they?
Hello, is this the chief?
Yeah, it's me.
We found a hidden room in the basement.
They have a huge tablet
there, probably a poneglyph,
and a massive collection of research
documents discussing the ancient texts.
Nice work.
Clerk.
Well, scholars of Ohara,
I'm afraid your death sentence
has already been decided.
It's a pity.
I hate to lose so many fine scholars,
but you're really forcing my hand here
Wow, what a letdown.
I came all this way just to say that?
Guess we'd better report
to the five elder stars.
Roger
Professor, they aren't
really going to kill you?
They wouldn't do that to someone for
just learning about history, would they?
Stupid brat, what do you know?
They may say they're
learning about history,
but the truth is they're
learning how to revive
an ancient weapon so they
can commit mass murder.
You're wrong!
They would never do anything like that!
Don't bother, Robin.
It's pointless to discuss the
matter with an errand boy like him.
What's that?
Is it really the ancient weapon itself
that the world government is afraid of?
Professor!
Be careful!
They're on the line now,
Chief. Good. Hold on! Eh?
Before you put all of us to death, allow
me to speak to the five Elder Stars.
Although we still have much to learn,
we have proudly continued
our research for many years.
So at the very least,
I would like to share our hypothesis on
the blank century with the world's leaders.
Heh, stubborn old fart. Hey! Yes, sir?
I'm begging you, please, get out of here!
If you hear what I have to
say, you'll become a criminal!
Professor!
Hey, it looks like they found the
people from the library guilty.
You gotta be kidding me!
Bad news!
There's a bunch of Navy battleships
closing in on the island from the east.
This is about to get real ugly.
We better evacuate now.
What is that?
It's a giant.
Where are you, Robin?
You've got to get off this
island before it's too late.
Have they made the order
for the Buster Call yet?
We're still on standby.
Hurry!
Run to the evacuation ship!
So this is a poneglyph, huh?
Yeah,
I heard even if we shoot it with a cannon,
it won't leave a single
scratch on the thing.
I can't believe these creepy things
are hidden all over the world.
I don't like it.
Is that so?
Yes, the evidence is clear.
This calls for nothing
short of the death penalty.
We're waiting for your order.
It's unfortunate.
Seeing as they've broken the law so
blatantly, there's really no other option.
We must enforce our own rules.
We don't need your mock
sympathy, Elder Stars.
Save your breath.
You're talking to the leaders
of the world, you damn criminal.
Show some respect.
That must be Professor Clover, Ohara's
foremost authority on archaeology.
I'm familiar with your work.
You've contributed much to
the world's cultural heritage.
It's sad to see a man of
your intellect go astray.
The history of this planet
belongs to all of mankind.
No matter what that history may be,
you don't have the right to
forbid us from learning it.
No one does. Professor.
If one can read the poneglyphs,
then it's also possible
that they can revive the
ancient weapons and place
the world in serious peril.
Even if you have the best of intentions,
someone else could come along
and use your research for evil.
Be it good or bad,
mankind has the responsibility to
accept whatever their history may hold.
As long as we don't succumb
to fear and ignorance,
we will be prepared for
anything that may come.
That's idealistic. Is it?
Or are you just making convenient
excuses to suit your needs?
In truth, there are two
mysteries left unsolved.
Of course we want to read the Poneglyph,
but the reason why they were made in
the first place is interesting as well.
Why was their message so important
that they had to inscribe
it on unbreakable stone to
pass on to future generations?
Why were they hidden and
scattered across the world?
Why were they not stored in a library?
The only logical conclusion is
that they feared their message
would be too easily destroyed
if they had written it on paper.
In other words, they had an enemy.
Someone who was afraid of the
information they wanted to pass on.
What are you trying to
imply, Professor Clover?
Since the ancients have disappeared,
we must assume that they were defeated
by this enemy And that whoever they were,
they survived through history
It may be no coincidence that roughly 800
years in the past When the blank century
came to an end The organization we now
call the World Government was founded
therefore if this unknown enemy was indeed
the world government it might be in their
best interest to erase this inconvenient
piece of information and let the ancients
disappear into a fabricated blank century
by analyzing ancient
manuscripts and piecing
together what we could
from the few pornoglyphs
we were able to find we discovered the
existence of a previously unknown country
although the details we found were a bit
scarce we believe it
was a grand and powerful
kingdom and yet despite their strength not
a trace remains or
rather those traces were
deliberately erased but they were prepared
for this possibility even as they faced
the threat of extinction and so they etched
their history in stone
before their kingdom
was crushed under the might of the allied
nations now known as the world government
thus the reason why the poneglyphs were
made becomes quite clear i see that's a
bold hypothesis it's true that the ancient
weapons would be a threat to the world but
more so than weapons
what i believe the world
government is afraid of is the history
surrounding this lost
kingdom its existence and
its ideologies are so
dangerous to you that
you would kill to keep
them secret although
we still don't know what makes you fear
this kingdom we do at least know its name
since we've gone so far already perhaps
Perhaps you'd like me to
share it with you now.
Kill him!
Professor!
You left us no choice.
How dare you! No! Professor!
Ohara knows too much.
You may give the order to attack.
Or don't move an inch! No!
You mustn't let anyone escape!
Now then, with a golden transponder snail
entrusted to me by Admiral Sengoku...
Professor!
Robin!
You fool!
I told you to run! Hurry!
I invoked the Buster Call!
And that's a wrap.
He pressed something!
What is that?
Get out of here! Go!
No!
I don't want to be alone!
You have to stop being so selfish!
This isn't the time!
Robin!
It's the Buster Call!
All battleships to your positions!
Prepare to open fire!
What?
Hey, look!
The Tree of Knowledge is on fire!
Dammit, what are you doing?
Are you insane?
Isn't it enough to take our lives?
Hey, it's not my fault.
Must have caught fire when they
bombed your secret basement.
Stop this! Right now!
You can't replace the documents in there!
Don't you realize that?
You don't move!
Whoa.
We don't need guns anymore.
Time for the government
agents to pull out.
Protect the books.
Let's put out the fire. Hurry!
Pass the water over here.
Carry as many books outside as you can.
Bring that woman with you.
Get up.
There's still some info we
have to ring out of her!
She can't die yet.
Just make sure she doesn't escape again.
Mommy!
Please, Robin, run while you still can.
You can't die here.
Not like this.
Mommy, no!
Go!
We're done for.
There's no point in staying.
Robin!
Robin, don't!
You're my mother, aren't you?
Make up your mind, Olvia.
Are you going to board this ship or not?
I'm holding her back.
Just hurry and get on.
Molly!
I'm sorry, Robin.
I can never call myself your mother again.
After all these years, after all I've
done, I don't have the right anymore.
Monster!
She's so scary, her mom ran away!
Hey, that's my daughter's
dress, you take it off!
I'm sorry Aunt Roji, I
just wanted to try it on!
You sure eat a lot for a freeloader.
Please answer me!
Are you my mom?
Hold on.
That girl your daughter or what?
No.
Oh yeah I'm sorry little girl you
must be confusing me with someone else
even if it comes to this I don't want
you to be the daughter of a criminal.
Oh yeah huh what a weird
little brat right let's go!
It's me! It's Robin!
I've grown since the last time,
so maybe you don't recognize me.
I've been waiting for you all these years.
Are you sure?
You're really...
Not my mom!
Just once, someday,
I wanted to hold your hand and
walk together like a family.
I studied hard to become an archaeologist
so I could go to sea with you.
I can read the Poneglyphs too.
What did she say?
Robin, no!
So please, look at me.
Let me stay with you.
Mom!
Robin.
I've waited so long.
We're finally together.
Don't leave me alone again.
Oh, no!
Now what's going on?
Now commencing the Buster Call.
All ships fire at once.
Everything on the island
of Ohara is your target.
Let nothing remain.
The research conducted here was far
more extensive than we anticipated.
Make sure that knowledge is not passed on.
Do not allow it to leave the island.
Annihilate the devils of Ohara.
Turn it to the ground.
In the name of justice!
Damn it! What the hell?
Can't you wait till we leave the island?
You're gonna kill us! Stop it!
The three of knowledge took a direct hit!
They're using their
highest power against us.
They staged their investigation, but
they were planning this from the start.
Bastards.
Hey, Chief, that girl said
she can read the Poneglyphs.
Yeah, she did, didn't she?
I don't know if it's true or not, though.
Probably safer to wipe
her out, just in case.
Don't let her leave the island.
Remember her face, all right?
We're retreating.
Then I'll grab Olvia.
Screw it!
The situation has changed!
Just run!
I'm not gonna get blown up trying
to follow some stupid order!
Our number one priority
is keeping me alive!
Retreat!
Everyone back to the ship!
Put out the fire on that
side before it spreads!
Protect the library at all costs!
I've been waiting a long time to do this.
I'm glad.
Robin!
Mommy!
Robin, forgive me.
Please.
This is my fault for not
watching over you with more care.
Is it really true that you
can read the pornoglyphs?
I had to learn, since I
wanted to be a scholar.
I never knew my little
girl was an archaeologist.
That's amazing.
You must have studied hard
while I was gone, huh?
These aren't things
that just anyone can do.
I'm so proud.
Fortunately,
the only ones who know about this are
the officials who were here earlier.
We can't afford to waste any more time.
Alpha, take Robin and run!
If you can sneak her
onto the evacuation ship,
she might still be able
to leave the island.
Robin!
I've been looking all
over for you. It's Saul.
So you met with your mother after all.
Sol, why in the world are you here?
Guess it must be fate.
I just happened to wash up here and your
little girl was the one who found me.
Anyhow, we ain't got
time to chat right now.
You gotta get off this island.
I'll be fine, but I need you to take
care of Robin for me, please. But why?
What about you?
Are you going to come with me?
Olivia, are you?
I can't leave yet.
There's something left to do.
No, Mom!
You can't leave me now!
I'll stay here with you!
I don't want to lose you again! Robin,
if you're a scholar of Ohara,
you should know that history
is mankind's greatest treasure.
Now that it's been passed on, it will
illuminate the path to your future.
However, you must pass it on as well,
or its light will disappear
with the next generation.
Share those books!
I won't take these!
We weren't trying to
uncover some dark secret,
we simply wanted to hear the voices
of the past and protect them.
Unfortunately,
our research ends here, but time
marches on, even if Ohara is destroyed.
And as surely as we believe in the past,
we believe in the future
that you will inherit.
What does that mean?
Someday, you'll know.
Hurry.
Take her and go, Saul!
Are you sure?
Yeah
Stop it!
I want to stay with you! Mommy! No!
I was happy to hear
you call me that again.
Thank you.
From now on.
For my sake as well?
You must live, Robin!
Vice Admiral Kuzan! What now?
It looks like...
No, wait, it's gotta be!
So are you gonna tell me or not?
Spit it out already, man!
It's the deserter!
Vice Admiral Saul!
Please don't!
You have to take me back! I can't!
There's no way!
Don't cry, Robin! Be proud!
Your mama's a wonderful woman!
Ohara's a wonderful place!
You gotta remember that!
It's up to you to pass it on, okay?
Ohara was so brave, they
fought against the whole world!
Are you crazy?!
Capturing them is enough!
They ain't even pirates, they're scholars!
Are you so weak you can't reel
them in without blowing them up?
We shoot down these researcher
ships one after another,
but I still can't find any sense
in killing these poor folks.
Vice Admiral Saul, we found a survivor!
You're nothing but murderers!
You're scholars.
Why do you need ancient weapons?
You don't know a thing.
You don't even know why you're killing us!
That's a Vice Admiral you're speaking to!
The weapons are just an excuse.
Why don't you try thinking about
what you're doing for once?
You're just afraid of a past
that you know nothing about!
This is a top-secret mission.
The Buster Call.
It's an Alto attack in which five
vice-admills command ten battleships.
I want you to take part.
They're just scholars, right?
Why do we have to go so far?
Even the ones we've captured before
don't seem like they care about weapons.
They just want to learn
more about history.
If their research is so dangerous, why
don't we help them so nothing goes wrong?
Least you can do is give me some
proof that these folks are bad.
Because to me, it seems like
we're the criminals here.
Are you questioning the government?
Just follow your orders.
I've got some questions for you.
You think we can talk?
This is an emergency!
Black Admiral Saul has taken
the prisoner and deserted!
This won't do.
He knows too much about our
next operation. After them.
Shots all will be at any cost.
Open fire if necessary.
Truth will be showing up any minute
now, but I'll take care of them.
You know, you won't be able to
return to the Navy after this.
Fine by me.
Now that I got this doubt in my heart,
ain't no point in staying anyway.
I know the law is the law, but the way
they're acting this time is downright cruel.
So I'm following my own sense of justice.
Now you get to that island
and warn your friends.
I'm not going to thank you.
Well, good luck to you either way.
Fire!
We're not targeting the
idol, we're not targeting me!
It hit him! I'm sorry!
Don't apologize!
He's the criminal's accomplice now!
My apologies, Robin.
that must have scared you.
Wait here a sec.
Are you the one firing at us?
What if you'd hurt that poor
little girl, you damn fools?
Vice Admiral, please stop!
I don't know about justice anymore,
but I do know I can protect my friend!
Stop it, Saul!
You're scaring me!
Hope you're ready,
because if you make an enemy out of
me, there's gonna be hell to play!
I want to tell you
what I want to say.
I can't tell you
what I
want to say.
Now, the light of a single one.
I feel that I've found.
If I can follow it,
I'll run away from the future!
I won't stay.
Once again, once again.